Dikshitkumar N

Software Developer

+91 9600714338 dikshitkumarnegmail.com <u>Dikshitkumar N</u> (Linkedin) dikshit-n (Github)

Summary

Software developer with 3 years and 7 months of experience in web development and currently extending my knowledge in mobile app development and more backend services. I believe in "learning by doing" which served me a lot and helps me to grow day-by-day in my career.

Skills

React JS - Advanced Next JS - Beginner Node JS - Beginner React Native - Beginner Typescript

Basic knowledge on AWS concepts, Jenkins, Docker, Github actions, Git, GraphQL

Professional Experience

Front-end Lead - iResponsive Solutions

January 2024 - Present

Currently leading a front-end team whose responsibilities are to build a forum based **React Native** mobile app and a web app for the same using **React JS**.

Software developer - Contract based developer at SSENSE from iResponsive Solutions

August 2022 - January 2024

Worked as a contract based developer at SSENSE from iResponsive Solutions in a project that includes technologies like React JS, React Native, Node JS, Micro services and Vue JS.

Gained knowledge on Docker, AWS concepts (project requirements), Github actions, Jenkins

Front-end Lead - AVEON InfoTech

July 2022 - December 2022

Led a front-end team to build a web app with React JS for maintaining the admin responsibilities of a blood donor application and a mobile app built with React Native for user side interaction.

Front-end Developer - AVEON InfoTech

April 2022 - June 2022

Worked on a minor React project under fee module of school management system. Improved my knowledge on ui-component libraries like **Material UI** and **Fluent UI**. Utilized the time to have a fundamental learning on **Node JS**.

Front-end Developer - Leora Solutions LLC

July 2021 - April 2022

Become strong with my client interaction skills and fluent with React JS and more in-hand experience on React JS by working on nearly 3 real-time projects remotely under the domains **Business Management**, **Digitalization and School management** for a client at Dubai.

Became strong with the concept of redux (redux and redux toolkit), authentication workflow in react and developing customised ui-components and hooks.

Gained basic knowledge on React Native, GraphQL, React Query.

Front-end Developer (Contract Based) - Leora Solutions LLC

July 2020 - July 2021

Gained my **first client interaction** skills and in-hand experience on React JS by working on nearly 4 real-time projects remotely for a client at Dubai.

Learned redux, authentication workflow in react, graphical UI implementations.

Freelance Web developer

July 2020 - August 2020

Built a landing page using **React JS** with complicated UI and smooth animations meeting the requirements of the client.

My Work: https://emergeability.org/

Software Developer Intern - Nanban tech ventures

June 2020 - July 2020

As a foundation for my aspiring career development, internship at this organisation provided me with the fundamental knowledge on web development and a great opportunity to upscale my career.

Personal Projects

Live Apps - Accounts

React JS, Fluent UI, Social authentication (front-end)

An **identity server** responsible to store user details in a centralised platform limited for applications partnering with <u>live apps</u> (<u>organization link</u>).

Single handedly contributed to build the front-end part using the technologies **React JS** and **Fluent UI** for developing the user interface with required redirects for the social authentication.

Documented the usage instruction of this identity server.

Repository link: https://github.com/live-apps-in/ui-accounts/blob/master/README.md
Documentation link: https://exciting-bassoon-bbe.notion.site/Accounts-Live-Apps-bc87388482a847ce91e902e80ff10951

Live Apps - Landing Page

React JS, Material UI (front-end)

Landing Page to showcase and describe the technologies and partnering applications built under <u>Live</u> <u>Apps</u>.

Repository link: https://github.com/live-apps-in/live-apps-landing-page/blob/main/README.md Lively deployed link: https://jaga.live/

Live Cord - Live Apps

React JS, Material UI (front-end)

Admin portal webpage to manage the discord bot (<u>kitty chan</u>) permissions and user privileges. **Single handedly contributed** on front-end part for this requirement.

Repository link: https://github.com/live-apps-in/ui-live-cord

NPM package - util-functions-demo-lib-for-live-apps

Typescript

A npm package containing util functions for cookie manipulation, strings and numbers.

Repository link: https://github.com/dikshit-n/bp-npm-package/blob/master/README.md
Npm package link: https://www.npmjs.com/package/util-functions-demo-lib-for-live-apps

Fitness Plus

React JS, Typescript

A web application for tracking the daily fitness data of an individual.

Repository link: https://github.com/dikshit-n/fitness-plus/blob/main/README.md
Lively deployed link: https://fitness--plus.web.app/

Portfolio

React JS, Javascript

My own portfolio built with react js. This is not up-to-date yet

 $Repository\ link:\ \underline{https://github.com/dikshit-n/portfolio/blob/main/README.md}$

Lively deployed link: https://portfolio-dikshit-n.vercel.app/

Education

Bachelor of Technology (IT)
Sri Krishna College of Engineering and Technology.